

# 艾怡華

# EVA VIRGINIA ARÉVALO RIVARA

HSINCHU CITY, 300 · TAIWAN · 93.EVAR@GMAIL.COM

Passionate Machine Learning Researcher striving to incorporate machine learning to the workflow of real-world tasks to expedite the process and render it more efficient. Hands-on experience with state-of-the-art NLP models (BERT) and implementing deep learning models (Tensorflow/PyTorch) for NLP applications; as well as more traditional supervised and unsupervised learning tools. Acquainted with performing classification and more general heuristic tasks through Genetic Algorithms and Pattern Recognition techniques. Experience crawling and processing datasets from Social Media platforms (Twitter). Fundamental understanding of Parallel Programming.

# **EDUCATION**

# NATIONAL TSING HUA UNIVERSITY

September 2018 - Present

#### MS. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

#### HSINCHU CITY, TAIWAN

Research work performed under the guidance of Prof. Chen Yi-Hsin. Focused on the application of Machine Learning techniques to detect Manic Episodes in Bipolar users in Social Media Platforms.

GPA: 4.27

# NATIONAL TSING HUA UNIVERSITY

September 2014 - June 2018

#### **BS. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE**

HSINCHU CITY, TAIWAN

## NATIONAL TAIWAN NORMAL UNIVERSITY

September 2013 - August 2014

#### **INTENSIVE MANDARIN STUDIES**

TAIPEI CITY, TAIWAN

# **SKILLS**

## PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES

C, C++, Python, Java, SQL, MySQL, MATLAB, Arduino, Verilog

## MACHINE LEARNING & DEEP LEARNING

# ΑĪ

- Clustering (k-means/DBSCAN)
- PCA / TSNE
- Classification / Linear Regression
- ▼ Time Series
- Genetic Algorithms (GA)
- Pattern Recognition

- Tensorflow / Keras /
  Tensorhub
- Pytorch
- CNNs, RNNs, LSTMs, GANs
- Deep contextual representations (ELMo, BERT)

### WEB DEVELOPMENT

- HTML5 / CSS / JavaScript
- ✓ NodeJs / Flask
- React / Bootrstrap
- MySQL / PostGreSQL / mongoDB
- Amazon Web Services
  (AWS) EC2, S3, RDS
  Services
- Docker
- Web visualizations with d3.js & Neo4j

# **MISCELLANEOUS**

- Parallel Programming
- CUDA Programming

# **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# NATIONAL TSING HUA UNIVERSITY

September 2019 - January 2020

#### **TEACHER ASSISTANT**

HSINCHU CITY, TAIWAN

Teacher Assistant for the Data Mining: Concepts, Techniques, and Applications course, offered by Prof. Chen Yi-Hsin, National Tsing Hua University, Institute of Information Systems and Applications (ISA 5810, Fall 2019).

### NATIONAL TSING HUA UNIVERSITY

February 2019 - June 2019

#### **TEACHER ASSISTANT**

HSINCHU CITY, TAIWAN

Teacher Assistant for the Data Structures course offered by Prof. Chen Yi-Hsin, National Tsing Hua University, Computer Science Department (CS 2351, Spring 2019).

# **EMBASSY OF CANADA**

July 2013 - August 2013

#### **IMMIGRATION PROGRAM REGISTRY CLERK**

**GUATEMALA CITY, GUATEMALA** 

Podcasting operational change management inside of workflows to establish a framework. Taking seamless key performance indicators offline to maximise the long tail. Keeping your eye on the ball while performing a deep dive on the start-up mentality to derive convergence on cross-platform integration.

#### June 2013 - June 2013

# **EMBASSY OF CANADA**

#### RECEPTIONIST AND SWITCHBOARD OPERATOR

**GUATEMALA CITY, GUATEMALA** 

Assisting and expediting the processing of visa applications. Managing and maintaining the storing of visa applications. Performing general office administration duties.

# **TELUS INTERNATIONAL**

July 2013 - August 2013

#### **CUSTOMER SERVICE REPRESENTATIVE (FRENCH LANGUAGE DIVISION)**

**GUATEMALA CITY, GUATEMALA** 

Customer Service Representative for online game platform Zynga. Assisting and providing information to customers.

# LANGUAGES & SOFT SKILLS

# **LANGUAGES**

- Spanish Native Proficiency
- French Native Proficiency
- **English -** Native Proficiency
- Chinese Professional Working Proficiency
- Japanese Beginner Proficiency

# **SOFT SKILLS**

- Strong sense of responsibility
- ✓ Aim for Efficiency and Excellency
- ▼ Good Organizational Skills
- Adaptability
- Proactive
- Pragmatic approach

# LICENCES & CERTIFICATES

# LEGAL TRANSLATION CERTIFICATE (ENGLISH-SPANISH)

December 2012

MINISTRY OF EDUCATION, GUATEMALA (MINEDUC)
GUATEMALA CITY, GUATEMALA

Authorized by the Ministry of Education, Guatemala to provide legal translation and interpretation services (Spanish-English).

evar\_resume.github.io is maintained by EvaArevalo.

This page is hosted by GitHub Pages.

View on GitHub